Jason Bongiovanni

Middle School Teacher





+82-10-8339-5835



Jpbongiovanni@gmail.com



linkedin.com/J-Bongiovanni



285 Itaewon-ro, Yongsan-gu, Seoul South Korea, 04347

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF ARTS INTERCULTURAL STUDIES Houghton College | Houghton, NY 2005 - 2009

MASTERS OF EDUCATION
EDUCATIONAL
TECHNOLOGY
American College of Education |
Online

SKILLS

Assessment and Evaluation
Curriculum Development
Differentiated Instruction
Classroom Management
Technological Integration
Global Competencies
PLCs

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Standards-Based Grading

MS OFFICE
GOOGLE DOCS
GOOGLE APPS
SCHOOLOGY
CLASS DOJO
BASECAMP
MAC AND WINDOWS OS
RUBICON ATLAS
POWER SCHOOL
CLASS CRAFT
DISCORD

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a passionate and hardworking teacher who aims to engage students and meet them where they are at in order to best equip them for real world challenges. I have spent eight years living and teaching in Seoul, South Korea, and I have traveled to many different countries. My philosophy of education can be summarized into two short questions: "What do I want my students to know?" and "What do I want them to do with that knowledge?" Learning and application go hand-in-hand. I hope to educate students in a way that teaches them the skills they need to be lifelong learners and problem solvers, seekers of truth, and to succeed in all areas of life.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

THEOLOGY, ETHICS AND VALUES TEACHER 07/16-Present Yongsan International School of Seoul | Seoul, South Korea

- Facilitate classroom curriculum and instruction in the analysis and application of ancient Biblical literature
- Implement worldview development instruction and appropriate worldview communication and discussion
- Design and create lesson plans in philosophy and theology education
- Collaborate with colleagues to develop standards and curriculum maps for 6th, 7th and 8th grade
- Integrate technology in the classroom to enhance student learning experience
- Facilitate student engagement by use of visual thinking and Kagan strategies

ASSISTANT ATHLETIC TRAINER

11/17 - Present

Yongsan International School of Seoul | Seoul, South Korea

- Assists head coaches in physical therapy for students
- Assists head coaches in team workout sessions with the development of high intensity interval training programs
- Coach students in basic fundamentals of Olympic lifting, weight lifting, and high intensity interval training
- Instruct students in proper weight room behavior and use of weight machines and free weights
- Design and implemented rehab and weight lifting programs for students

ENGLISH INSTRUCTOR

10/11 - 09/15

Chungdham April Institute | Seoul, South Korea

- Presented Chungdham April material to children ranging from ages
 7-12
- Monitored students' ability to speak, read, and think critically on a wide variety of subjects
- Facilitated group discussions and debates on a broad spectrum of topics to evaluate student achievement

CERTIFICATIONS

English Grades 6-12 Social Science Grades 6-12 Teacher Ready Florida dep. of Education October 2015 - May 2016

> TEFL 120-Hour Cert. Boston Language Institute December 2009

> Crossfit Level 1 Trainer Crossfit Inc. October 2017

PROFFSSIONAL **DEVELOPMENT**

Standards to Benchmarks John Glasgow 03/01/2018

How to Create Fair and Effective Assessments Brian Remsburg 09/22/2016

Effective Grading and Reporting for All Students University or Institution

REFERENCES

SUSAN SEVEY Principal Yongsan International School of Seoul +82(2) 797-5104 Susan.Suvey@yisseoul.org

MARK ROSENBAUM Assistant Principal Yongsan International School of Seoul +82(2) 797-5104 Mark.Rosenbaum@yiseeoul.org

TEACHING EXPERIENCE Continued

ENGLISH INSTRUCTOR

05/10 - 05/11

Chungdahm Learning | Incheon South Korea

- Instructed students ranging from ages 10-15 in English learning material
- Evaluated the students' achievement through discussions, tests, debates, and project based learning

TEACHING RELATED EXPERIENCE

Masters of Educational Technology American College of Education | Online

May '18 – Present

- Exploring a diverse array of digital tools to enhance learning and student experience in the classroom
- Developing pedagogical skills and strategies to support learning through technology, including blending
- Training in strategies to provide professional development and technical assistance to teaching staff

Student Teaching

Oct. '15 – May '16

Yongsan International School of Seoul | Seoul, South Korea

- Assisted mentor instructor in classroom activities in 7th grade geography
- Taught mentor's class for one full week at the culmination of student teaching
- Participated in student learning trips and extracurricular activities
- Collaborated in teacher grade level meetings
- Facilitated lessons and student debates
- Created lesson plans and student activities

Study Abroad Program in Tanzania

Jan. '08 - May.

'08 Houghton College | Iringa, Tanzania

- Studied and focused on aspects of life in Eastern Africa including: anthropology, wildlife, history, folklore, and Swahili
- Lived among the different social classes and tribal groups of the area, which allowed for greater understanding of the culture

Teacher Ready

Oct. '15 - May '16

Yongsan International School of Seoul | Seoul, South Korea

- Completed Teacher Ready's eight month online certification program through the Florida department of education
- Received instruction on Standards based pedagogy, classroom management, procedures, and rules
- Participated in student teaching at Yongsan International School of Seoul with a 7th grade classroom mentor
- Assisted my classroom mentor in teaching, classroom management, lesson planning and administration.
- Passed Florida Department of Education's subject area exams in grades 6-12 Social Sciences and English Literature

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

2016 - 2018 | Week Without Walls MS Program | Y.I.S.S.

2016 - 2018 | Intermural Soccer Referee | Y.I.S.S.

2016 -2018 | Intermural Basketball Referee | Y.I.S.S.

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- -Ultimate Frisbee Competed fort he #1 National level club team in South Korea
- -Crossfit Since 2011. Level 1 certification acquired in 2017
- -Video/Board Games recreational and for educational use
- -Philosophy /Theology Discussion and debate, apologetics
- -Hiking General outdoor activities and fitness